<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mavlink>
  <version>3</version>
  <dialect>0</dialect>
  <enums>
    <enum name="MAV_MISSION_STATE">
      <description>Type of mission items being requested/sent in mission protocol.</description>
      <entry value="0" name="MAV_MISSION_CURRENT">
        <description>Items are mission commands for main auto mission and are received via the autopilot and aircraft module.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="1" name="MAV_MISSION_ONBOARD">
        <description>Items are mission ready and have been acknowledged by the aircraft module for processing.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="2" name="MAV_MISSION_PROPOSED">
        <description>Items are mission ready but have been generated by a module not related to the aircraft and need to be pushed towards the appropriate aircraft module.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="3" name="MAV_MISSION_RECEIVED">
        <description>Items have been distributed and received by the appropriate MACE instance connected to the associated module. They however have yet to be marked as current or onboard. Often this state is reflected via communication between external link modules.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="4" name="MAV_MISSION_OUTDATED">
        <description>Items were once relevant to the system have been since replaced with newer current missions.</description>
      </entry>
    </enum>
  </enums>

  <messages>

    <message id="12500" name="NEW_ONBOARD_MISSION">
      <description>This message is emitted currently under one circumstances. A vehicle may emit this when its local planners have developed a new mission for the vehicle and have updated one of its queues. The count of the mission items in this queue is sent as its more direct method of enabling other mace instances for transmission</description>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="mission_system">Mission System ID</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="mission_creator">Creator ID</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="mission_id">Mission ID</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="mission_type" enum="MISSION_TYPE">Mission type, see MISSION_TYPE</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="mission_state" enum="MISSION_STATE">Mission type, see MISSION_STATE</field>
    </message>

    <message id="12501" name="REQUEST_HOME_POSITION">
      <description>The home position relating to the mission of the target system has been requested.</description>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="target_system">The system which the home position is being requested from.</field>
    </message>

    <message id="12502" name="HOME_POSITION_ACK">
      <description>An acknowledgement of setting the home position.</description>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="target_system">System ID</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="ack">Acknowledgement of the home position set request.</field>
    </message>

    <message id="12503" name="GUIDED_TARGET_STATS">
      <description>Message containing stats relating to the aircrafts perception of a current target position along a trajectory and its distance.</description>
      <field type="float" name="x">X position of this position in the defined coordinate frame.</field>
      <field type="float" name="y">Y position of this position in the defined coordinate frame.</field>
      <field type="float" name="z">Z position of this position in the defined coordinate frame.</field>
      <field type="float" name="distance">Relative distance away the system is from the target location.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="coordinate_frame">Coordinate frame of the position vector. This field is as related to the MAV_FRAME definition.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="state">Current state of the controller in pursuit of the guided state.</field>
    </message>
 
  </messages>
</mavlink>
